JAN DENNISON

Web Developer

{ email: jldennison@gmail.com, phone: (614) 370-3431, website: jannypie.github.io };

As someone who loves both coding and design, I delight in bridging front-end and back-end development. My work reflects thoughtfulness, persistence, and an ability to adapt. I bring together these skills and strengths to meet the challenge of the ever-evolving user experience.

TECH STACK

HTML, CSS, SCSS/Sass, JavaScript, jQuery, JS libraries, AJAX, API, JSON, REST, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, RSpec/TDD, SQL, Git, SVN

EXPERIENCE

Dev Bootcamp

Full Stack Web Development Student

2014 - 2015

- Attended 19-week intensive code school program to supplement front-end experience by learning programming languages, database creation and querying, development frameworks, and web serving and deployment
- Additional strong focus placed on Agile workflow, pair-programming, test-driven development, engineering empathy, development best practices, providing feedback, and building community
- Final Project: Development resume/portfolio builder with GitHub/Twitter APIs, built in a week devolio.herokuapp.com

Abercrombie & Fitch

Front End Developer

2013 - 2015

- Built and tested desktop and mobile web pages using eCommerce product data for cross-browser/cross-platform performance and compatibility according to project requirements and team direction
- Prototyped concepts bridging design and development, such as merging mobile and desktop code bases into single responsive UI and codebase for abercrombie.com
- Expanded front-end codebase (HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery, JSP, JSTL) to translate design & project directives into dynamic and interactive website presentation layers

Art Brands Inc. Web Developer

2013 - 2013

Extended eCommerce platform front-end codebase for design, UX, and performance needs and launched new online store website
using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

irisnote (formerly Rescentris)

Web Designer / Digital Marketing Specialist

2011 - 2013

- Led corporate website re-design and re-branding processes, was responsible for all website administration tasks including content migration and management, domain registration, web hosting, URL pathing/redirects, SEO
- Created and developed website elements using Photoshop, HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, PHP; wrote custom HTML5 web forms with client-side JS validation
- Managed all print and online content including articles, press releases, newsletters, press kit, information videos, graphic elements, social media posts, branding guide and materials, booth materials for trade shows, product brochures, and business cards

Freelance

Graphic / Web Designer

2007 - 2014

• Designed websites, blogs, logos, branding, and advertising elements from Photoshop to HTML/CSS for variety of individuals and small businesses on a part-time freelance basis

Battelle Memorial Institute

Research Associate

2004 - 2010

- Led complicated research experiments from start to finish, resulting in experience managing multiple tasks simultaneously, professional client interaction, effective task communication and reporting, and strong team building skills
- Held DOD Secret Clearance, DOJ clearance for work with Select Agents; received multiple Outstanding Performance Awards for project support and management

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science, Biology

Ohio Northern University, Graduation with Honors

VOLUNTEER

Co-Chapter Leader, Teacher, TA Girl Develop It!

2014-Current

2004